Between the innocent, the romantic, the sensual, and the unthinkable.
There are still some things we have yet to imagine.
Sophie's Choice is a drama, romance, war film directed by Alan J. Pakula.
Stingo, a young writer, moves to Brooklyn in 1947
to begin work on his first novel.
As he becomes friendly with Sophie and her lover Nathan, he
learns that she is a Holocaust survivor.
Flashbacks reveal her harrowing story, from pre-war prosperity to Auschwitz.
In the present, Sophie and Nathan's relationship increasingly unravels as Stingo grows
closer to Sophie and Nathan's fragile mental state becomes ever more apparent.
Zofia "Sophie" Zawistowski, played by Meryl Streep.
Nathan Landau, played by Kevin Kline.
Stingo, played by Peter MacNicol.
Yetta, played by Rita Karin.
Morris Fink, played by Josh Mostel.
Lillian Grossman, played by Robin Bartlett.
Sophie's Choice is a 1982 psychological drama  directed and written by Alan J.
Pakula, adapted from William Styron's 1979 novel.
The film stars Meryl Streep as Zofia "Sophie" Zawistowska, a Polish immigrant who moves to America with a dark secret from her past, who shares a
boarding house in Brooklyn with her tempestuous lover Nathan (Kevin Kline in his feature-film debut), and young writer Stingo (Peter MacNicol).
It also features Rita Karin, Stephen D.
Newman, and Josh Mostel in supporting roles.
Sophie's Choice premiered in Los Angeles on December 8, 1982, and was
theatrically released on December 10 by Universal Pictures.
It received positive reviews from critics and
grossed $30 million at the box office.
Streep's performance was highly praised.
The film received five nominations at the 55th Academy Awards, for Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Cinematography,
Best Costume Design, and Best Original Score, with Streep winning the award for Best Actress.
The film explores themes of new york city, concentration
camp, holocaust (shoah), world war ii, writer.
The tone is emotional.